<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michal Šrámek</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michal Šrámek</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Magic of SAP: A Comprehensive Guide for Begginers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/magic-of-sap-comprehensive-guide-for-begginers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/magic-of-sap-comprehensive-guide-for-begginers/</guid>
      <description>In the process of our IT life, each of us will surely encounter the word SAP one day. But what is actually SAP and how does it actually work? The official vendor documentation is clear on this and defines SAP as following: SAP is one of the world’s leading producers of software for the management of business processes. That is not entirely clear. Even a literal German translation - Systemanalyse Programmentwicklung - will not help us too much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity Monitoring and Audit in AWS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/activity-monitoring-and-audit-in-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/activity-monitoring-and-audit-in-aws/</guid>
      <description>Following text involves AWS native tools for the continuous monitoring of activities within an AWS environment to detect and respond to security threats and breaches.&#xA;It encompasses the discovery collection of best practices, how to achieve this goal. Implementing this secure Activity Monitoring and Audit in AWS, will enhance security posture, mitigate risks, and better protect all AWS resources and sensitive data from unauthorised access or malicious activities.&#xA;Every decision made in AWS environment should be in accordance with the AWS Security Reference Architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortress GitHub: Building a Secure Organization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/fortress-github-building-secure-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/fortress-github-building-secure-organization/</guid>
      <description>Authentication security on the GitHub platform is a key aspect of protecting corporate data and securing user accounts. Usually, we rely not only on standard methodologies (passwords, 2FA) but also on the significant benefits of centralized access control and easy integration with an external identity service. In this way, we could contribute to an overall increase in the level of security. SAML (Security Assertion Markup Language) is a standard for exchanging authentication and authorization data between security domains, often used for Single Sign-On (SSO) across web applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub: Personal Access Tokens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/github-personal-access-tokens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/github-personal-access-tokens/</guid>
      <description>There are currently 2 types of personal access tokens (PATs) available on GitHub. Fine-grained PATs (beta) and Classic PATs. Both are used for authentication and authorization, but have different properties and uses. There is no Token like Token.&#xA;Fine-grained PATs (beta) Classic PATs Purpose Token for GitHub API for scripting or testing. OAuth personal access tokens OR Instead of a Git password via HTTPS OR For API authentication via Basic Authentication.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
